Theme Tune: [music playing]
Al: Hello Farmers and welcome to another episode of The Harvest Season. My name is Al and we're
Chelsea: My name is Chelsea.
Al: here today to talk about cottagecore games. Woo. Chelsea's back. Chelsea's becoming the
Al: most common co-host apparently. Well let's yeah let's wait till we've got through the
Chelsea: No emergencies this week for anybody, I hope.
Al: episode before we decide that because I don't think you were expecting at the beginning.
Chelsea: No.
Al: Everyone is fine. Everyone is fine. There are no leftover problems so we're all good.
Al: This episode we're going to talk about some demos. I played some demos. Chelsea played
Al: some demos. We're going to talk about those demos. Woo. Before that we have news but first
Chelsea: Yes.
Al: of all Chelsea what have you been up to?
Chelsea: Um, so I played a few demos, I went to a wedding last week, went to a baby shower,
Chelsea: uh, busy, busy time, and we got our Wii U back up and running, so we've been trying out some of
Chelsea: the older games there. Um, one of my favorites was WarioWare. I love those games, smooth moves,
Al: Ah.
Al: Yeah.
Al: Love a good WarioWare.
Chelsea: I was obsessed with that game, so we're trying to just get back into the hang of that and
Chelsea: looking to get our rock band stuff set back, uh, set up back, which is more expensive now,
Al: Nice.
Chelsea: I wish we didn't get rid of it, but when we moved, we were like, I don't even want to look
Chelsea: at this stuff, even though we had a full attic that we could store it in, but now I'm trying to
Chelsea: find places to buy it and people, I guess, realize that they're expensive now, so. But the new one's
Al: Yeah it's a different company, it's a different game series. I can't remember what it's called.
Chelsea: Because it was Neversoft, right?
Al: So this, oh what's it called? Stage Tour is the new one.
Chelsea: Oh, okay.
Chelsea: Make the kids emo again!
Al: Yeah I'm debating whether to get it or not. Obviously I want it but it is a lot of money,
Al: It's like a hundred and twenty pou-
Al: pounds for the game and controller, and it's like that is a lot of money, um, bought.
Chelsea: Oh, okay.
Chelsea: Yeah.
Chelsea: Apparently they made one on the 3DS, Guitar Hero, and I think I- That's not the same thing!
Al: It had, yeah, it had like a little grip that you would put on to the 3DS and it had the
Al: same five buttons, it's just you held it like the 3DS, like a star. It's very silly.
Chelsea: Oh my gosh, I couldn't do it.
Al: I'm just looking up, apparently, so Stage Tour is being made by Red Octane, who wear
Al: of Guitar Hero. But, well, it's probably one of these things where, I think multiple people
Chelsea: Oh, okay. What am I thinking of Neversoft then?
Chelsea: What are they doing?
Al: have done these things. Yeah, Neversoft did Guitar Hero from 2007, Red Octane did, no
Al: wait, yeah, so Red, oh it might be that they were both, so Red Octane produced it? I don't
Al: know what the difference is.
Al: The new Red Octane is here. They're both listed as having done Guitar Hero, but Red Octane are doing the new one, which is called Stage Tour.
Chelsea: Okay.
Chelsea: Alrighty.
Al: But I'm trying to figure out what the deal is because Red Octane was closed by Activision in 2010.
Chelsea: Come back to her.
Al: So a new Red Octane was opened.
Al: In 2025, with the co-founders of Cracked, who they're the ones that make the Nitro deck that I talk about.
Al: They're like the grip, the like controller grip for the Switch and Switch 2.
Chelsea: Yeah. Oh.
Al: And they also they've been making controllers for like Guitar Hero and Clone Hero and stuff like that for a long time.
Al: They make a lot of accessories, so apparently they...
Al: ...started this new Red Octane with the former head and VP of operations at Blizzard reading the studio.
Chelsea: Interesting.
Chelsea: Oh my god.
Chelsea: Teenage me in shambles right now.
Chelsea: All these, all these things together.
Al: So I wonder how they got the name from Activision?
Chelsea: I don't know.
Chelsea: Tangent number one.
Al: Oh, in fact, the co-founders of Cracked, they were the co-founders of the original Red Octane,
Al: so maybe they still owned the name.
Al: So that explains why they then started making random guitar controllers because that's
Al: what they'd done.
Chelsea: [LAUGHS] Cool.
Al: Very interesting.
Al: Anyway, I did not realize this, so this is, this is, the new ones are being made by the
Al: original people who founded Red Octane and they were part of the team that did the original
Al: guitar heroes, but presumably they don't.
Chelsea: very cool would we consider that a cozy game because we could play it at home here with
Chelsea: your friends you could be nice and cozy with the fireplace on in the background
Al: Yeah, all right, cool, so yes, rock star, rock band, star, tour, guitar, hero.
Chelsea: yes
Chelsea: guitar star
Chelsea: what have you been up to, Al?
Al: What have I been up to?
Al: Well, I have also been playing demos and I have started playing the new Wolverine game.
Chelsea: Oh, I'm curious for your thoughts on that one.
Al: Thoughts are mixed. I...
Al: I enjoy the combat. The combat I think is very good. It's very similar to the Spider-Man
Al: combat. Obviously you don't have webs but it still seems to get the speed of combat
Al: down quite well. So I think it works quite well. But we'll see how I feel by the end
Al: of the game. I think the thing that most people seem to be getting caught up on this, if you
Al: ignore the people who are like "Oh I can't believe it's really easy when you turn all
Al: the settings to easy.
Al: - If you ignore that,
Al: I think most of the legitimate criticism
Al: seems to be that it's very linear
Al: and that is frustrating some people.
Al: And I get that.
Al: I also agree that generally I prefer less linear games
Al: in this sort of style.
Al: I think it depends.
Al: I like some linear games, I like some non-linear games.
Al: I think the problem is this is a game being built
Al: by the people who did "Spider-Man,"
Al: And Spider-Man is, like, THE MOST OPEN GAME.
Al: Like, if you're thinking about a game that's open...
Chelsea: I was gonna say, you cannot do the same game twice.
Al: Yeah, yeah, if you think of a game that is open world,
Al: like, that is gonna be high up on the list of the most open.
Al: And this is, like, so far down the list of open
Al: that it's basically levels, right?
Al: Like, as you go through the game, you go to an area
Al: and you have to progress through it to get to the end.
Al: And there are things you can do along the way.
Al: There's, like, some secrets and stuff throughout the levels,
Al: but you play level and then you continue on. I have not found a way as of yet to go back to previous
Al: levels but I presume it will happen at some point, considering you can finish the level
Al: without getting all of the collectibles and stuff. But I'm not a huge amount, I'm only
Al: maybe like two and a bit hours into the game or something, trying to find time as you will
Al: know is murder. So I'm not hugely through so I don't know how far through that will
Al: Unlock but yeah as I like I'm nearly finished the second level.
Al: I've not seen any way to get through it back to the first level
Al: As of yet, so I don't know whether that's possible whether you have to wait till you finish the game to go back
Al: I don't know
Al: So I think I understand I totally understand why people don't like that and personally I would prefer less of that
Al: But here's the thing. I don't think this game would be fun being open-world because I like your
Al: when you're spider-man
Al: You are whizzing around
Al: the world super fast. You're webbing around, you're zooming around, it's great. Wolverine just isn't
Al: as fast and isn't as movable, right? Like, he's never going to be as enjoyable to move around
Al: as Spider-Man. And yes, I am a... exactly, exactly, exactly. And I understand that there are
Chelsea: Well, now you're not climbing off the ceilings and...
Al: open world games where you are not, you know, whizzing around super fast, but they're not as fun
Al: In my opinion, so.
Al: I don't think I would enjoy this game as much if it was, if it was open world.
Al: I understand people wanting it to be open world, I just, I don't think I would enjoy
Al: it as much.
Al: That doesn't mean that other people wouldn't enjoy it more, but I don't think I would enjoy
Al: it as much if it was open world.
Al: I think the level based thing works well for Wolverine, but I think, yeah, I do think that's
Chelsea: Yeah.
Chelsea: Okay, so it's a bit of a shock value going from Spider-Man to Wolverine expecting the similar experience.
Al: a big part of it.
Al: Also the tutorial level is the most like.
Al: Linear of linear things you can do and like it.
Al: The the tutorial level does seem to whether you have the setting on on or off. It does seem to auto complete the quick time events. I don't. It doesn't seem to do that in other levels. I think it's just because it's a tutorial level, but obviously the tutorial levels quite big because it like all of these levels are quite large. They're not like they're not the size of like a, you know, a Mario one level.
Al: that like think of them like
Al: kind of mario odyssey style size of levels right they're quite large they take you know you're
Chelsea: Okay. Okay.
Al: it can take an hour or so to get through one of these levels they're quite big
Al: so I think because of the tutorial level being the most linear um like the second level i'm on
Al: is much less linear than that um and that you can you know stop and do other things and like
Al: find things along the way and there are secrets and stuff like that.
Al: I think a lot of it is people, for some reason there are people who are going online and just
Al: lying and saying "oh I don't have this, I am on the hardest setting and I'm not dying" and you're
Al: like "no you're clearly not on the hardest setting, I have died in this game, you are just actively
Al: lying" and so there's a bit of that, there's a bit of people wanting it to fail because that's
Al: more fun for some people when things fail and you're never going to get over that and I don't
Al: don't really care, right? Like you can complain.
Al: and all you want. You can, fine, whatever. And then there's an aspect of it which is
Al: totally legitimate, which is, this is just not what I wanted. And I think part of that
Al: is because they announced this game without any indication as to what it was. They went,
Al: "Hey, we're making a Wolverine game. It's the people who made Spider-Man. The people
Al: who made Spider-Man are making a Wolverine game. And so of course those expectations
Al: are going to come up. You're never going to..." But I was always right from the start. I was
Al: always like, okay, I'm excited, but also like, how is this going to work? Because you can't
Al: be as fluid.
Al: and fast as Spider-Man. That's just not how it works. And so I was always a little bit
Al: wary about that. But yeah, it is what it is. I think if you don't like this type of game,
Al: if you don't like a more linear game, which is the other thing as well, is there's a lot
Al: of cutscenes because it's trying to tell a big story. And so I think maybe, you know,
Al: This is a guesstimate, but in my two and a half hours of…
Al: playing the game, there's, I think, maybe been about half an hour of cutscenes.
Al: Like, it's quite a lot. And there's obviously quite a lot of areas where it's
Al: kind of, you're walking between areas to get the story, rather than, like,
Al: the gameplay, and people don't like that. And I get that. I totally get that.
Al: So, I understand some of these… some of the criticisms of the game. I am still enjoying
Al: myself. The combat is still fun. I'm intrigued to see where the story goes. It's not like a typical
Al: X-Men story I'm very interested to see where this is going because it's like it's just the setup is
Al: very different from previous ones so I'm intrigued to see where it goes.
Chelsea: Oh, interesting. So, do you ride around on a bike, or do you just walk? Or run?
Al: There are some there are some bike levels but it's not like just in general so there's some
Chelsea: Okay. Okay.
Al: levels where you're on a bike and there's some levels where you're you're kind of running around
Al: you can run but yeah it's just they're not huge areas so it's more about like
Al: the area and you know killing the people right like it's Wolverine the point is you're stabbing
Al: people in the face. So if you're looking for a game that is you're stabbing bad people in
Chelsea: You are slicing people open!
Al: the face with your adamantium claws then you that's the game for you.
Al: So yeah I think that's I think that's why. The other thing I want to talk about is Bad
Al: Apples. Have you heard of Bad Apples? So this is a film this is a movie it's got
Al: Saoirse Ronan in it if you know who she is and she now you're gonna wonder why I'm talking about this
Chelsea: Okay, yes, yes, yes.
Al: right but I'll get to it I promise. So she plays a teacher who kidnaps a pupil
Al: because he's a terrible pupil she hates him he's like bad to him like he you know you're like he
Al: pushes one of the other pupils down the stairs and stuff like that and so she kidnaps him and
Al: and keeps him in her basement.
Chelsea: Okay.
Al: And you're gonna ask, "Is this a comedy?"
Al: Kind of.
Al: I think it's meant to be satire.
Al: So it's kind of got weird tonal differences.
Al: But the reason why I'm talking about this
Al: is a big part of the plot early on
Al: is her playing Farming Simulator.
Chelsea: No way.
Al: She has one game for her to relax in.
Chelsea: Is that her coping mechanism?
Al: It's Farming Simulator.
Chelsea: You see, you tied it in nicely.
Al: It's absolutely fantastic.
Al: It popped up, she sits down in front of her TV.
Al: I couldn't figure out which console it was.
Al: I didn't get a good look at the controller or the interface.
Al: And she just pops up and it's like,
Al: "Oh, just sitting on a tractor with the machinery
Chelsea: [sob]
Al: "and plowing the field."
Al: And I was like, "This is hilarious.
Al: "I love that."
Al: And of course.
Al: And like she even says the name of it at one point.
Al: So it's very, very definitely that that's what it is.
Al: It's just very funny.
Al: I've never seen that be in, you know, in a film before.
Al: It's very funny.
Chelsea: [laughs]
Al: So there we are.
Chelsea: Incredible.
Al: And I did enjoy the film.
Al: I thought it was very good.
Al: It's a little bit ridiculous, but I think it was very good.
Al: And I laughed.
Al: So there's some level of comedy there.
Al: There was a bit where I was laughing.
Al: The ridiculousness of it, but yeah, there we go. That's what we've been up to.
Chelsea: Interesting. Yeah. Woo.
Al: All right, let's talk about some news. First up, Gaucho Origins.
Al: So this is the new game by the people who did Gaucho on the grasslands,
Al: which is already out on Android, is now also out on iPhone and iPad.
Al: So if you were wanting to play this game, but you don't have an Android device, there you go.
Al: You can get it on your iPhone.
Al: Maybe we need to play it.
Al: It's for, yeah, yeah.
Chelsea: one that's like four dollars yeah okay oh on sorry on computer it's 25.99
Al: Next up.
Al: Oh, no.
Al: Yeah, it's a different game.
Al: The one on Steam is a different game, Gaucho on the grasslands.
Al: Gaucho Origins is a mobile game specifically.
Chelsea: oh okay oh
Al: So, yeah, different, different game.
Al: Next up, Moonlight and Garland have released a 2.0.0 M update.
Al: I think the M stands for mini-map.
Al: map because they've released a mini-map in the game
Al: And also you get a birthday gift on your birthday
Chelsea: Oh, cute.
Al: That's it
Chelsea: That's it.
Chelsea: You get a map and a birthday gift.
Al: Next up the ranchers have kind of summarized a bunch of small updates
Al: They've been doing since release and called it foundations update part one
Al: So they kind of list all the things that are in there
Al: I I don't think there's any huge things that would make sense to talk about if you've not played the game
Al: But I think if you tried the game on release day, and you're like, oh, there's a bunch of
Al: stuff that just doesn't feel right, this might have addressed that, because there's a lot
Al: of quality of life improvements and stuff like that, so. Yes, please do.
Chelsea: Can I please just read this one and animals now stay sick for longer before dying
Al: Good. Rip. Speaking of small updates, Tiny Eden have
Chelsea: Giving you much more time to react and visit the veterinarian. So I guess before they just kind of like collapsed and that was it
Chelsea: Yeah rip
Al: released 9 updates since their initial release.
Al: which was on the 7th of September.
Al: So they are zooming through their updates.
Al: Update one added save compatibility,
Al: gameplay and quests and localization.
Al: Update two changed some controls,
Al: and audio and localization.
Al: Three was changes to cooking, gardening, progression,
Al: and more localization.
Al: Update four added a field of view setting,
Al: some improvements to drones.
Al: Update five added some.
Al: Some changes to the UI controls, drones and quests fixes.
Al: Update six added a bunch of bug fixes for crashes and some changes to the game pad and
Al: quest progression.
Al: Update seven fixed a bunch of issues with the cafe and kitchen and also quests, drones,
Al: orders and more.
Al: Update eight added a way to report bugs and some fixes to drones, trading and more.
Al: And update nine has added a fully reworked garden beds, safer save handling.
Al: Which we all love.
Al: And improved laboratory cut scene, new drone screens, performance improvements.
Al: And I know, madness.
Chelsea: And if you look at the dates it's crazy it's all within like a week of each other.
Al: So there you are.
Al: They are zooming through that.
Al: So if you've complained about something in Tiny Eden, it may well already be fixed.
Chelsea: A totally different game by now.
Al: Well, it mostly sounds like bug fixes and quality of life improvements rather than,
Al: you know, big, big changes, but.
Al: - Yeah.
Al: And our final game update news
Al: is for Village in the Shade.
Al: So as a reminder, this is the game
Al: where their English version is coming out
Al: on the 27th of October.
Al: They have announced that they are releasing
Al: some free updates and some paid DLC.
Al: The free updates will include new furniture,
Al: new livestock, and a farmland expansion,
Al: The new livestock being silky chickens,
Al: mallards, fluffy cows and spotted goats.
Chelsea: adorable. They look like they have little afros, the cows.
Al: The paid DLC will include, they say, new mechanics, scenarios, maps and other unique
Al: events.
Al: I think this is a translation thing, because it's like, scenario, I think is like, quests?
Chelsea: That's what I was thinking like we're gonna put you in some new scenarios to figure out
Al: Yeah, it sounds so much like, this is the technical translation.
Al: The free updates will be coming on the 29th of September and the 27th of October.
Chelsea: Yes
Chelsea: Right all the graphics are
Al: I guess the second free update is the one that comes with the English language update.
Al: And the paid DLC will be coming out in spring of next year.
Chelsea: Oh, is this that horror game that Kevin and I talked about?
Al: I mean, there's lots of them, but yes, I think this one is.
Chelsea: The one that looks really cute and then.
Chelsea: OK, yeah, I think it was this one, OK.
Al: This is the one that says, "Just make sure you follow the rules or else."
Chelsea: I don't think fluffy cows are going to make me come to this game.
Al: So they've also announced a deluxe edition you can buy now, which includes a soundtrack
Chelsea: OK, yeah, yeah, yeah, gotcha.
Al: and an art book for the game.
Al: I will not be doing that, because I sometimes do that with games if they're really cheap
Al: and I've been enjoying the game and I want to give them a bit more money, but this game
Al: is 50 quid.
Al: So, I don't--
Al: I don't think I need to give them more money.
Al: I think 50 quid will be enough.
Al: All right.
Al: We've got some new games to talk about as well,
Al: which Chelsea has thoughts on.
Chelsea: Oh, okay.
Al: First up, first up, we have--
Al: Just get--
Al: Save your opinion for once I explain.
Al: First up, we have "Welcome to Elderfield."
Al: So, this is out now.
Al: It came out last week.
Al: "Welcome to Elderfield, a cozy horror RPG
Al: with hand-drawn art and dark lo-fi music.
Al: Befriend or romance the locals.
Al: Investigate mysteries.
Al: Decorate your home.
Al: Fight terrifying creatures.
Al: Fish, cook.
Al: Seek the old gods.
Al: Die in your sleep and more."
Al: There's lots to do in Elderfield.
Chelsea: Just throw that in there, die in your sleep!
Al: I love how it's like, "Oh, manage a farm.
Al: Befriend or romance the locals.
Al: Investigate mysteries.
Al: Decorate your home.
Al: Fight terrifying creatures.
Al: Fish, cook.
Chelsea: Fish? Cook?
Al: Seek the old gods.
Al: Die in your sleep."
Al: It's like just sandwiching some nice stuff
Chelsea: Oh.
Al: in amongst some horrifying stuff.
Chelsea: God, this looks terrifying, like, I had my- my Apple Watch on, and then as I'm watching the trailer I get the, like,
Chelsea: your heart rate is elevated.
Al: Oh no, we're killing Chelsea. Look, I don't know whether you ever heard the one, oh what
Chelsea: 'Cause I am just such a wuss. I am such a wuss.
Al: was it called? Pumpkin Panic was it? Pumpkin Panic, yeah. That was one we did for Halloween
Al: a few years ago and it was me and Kelly I think who did it. This one is a roguelite
Al: but it's like you're farming but there's also monsters nearby and sometimes they just come
Al: and kill you and if you manage if you
Chelsea: Oh. Oh my god. Absolutely not.
Al: manage to get back to your house they're just like smashing on the door trying to get in
Al: it's just the most horrifying thing because it's like you're always you're basically on a timer
Al: and eventually you will be killed if you don't manage to escape the garden
Al: um but yeah it's and it's like the lights when it gets dark you've just got this tiny
Al: little light that you're walking with and then you just see shadows coming it is horrifying
Chelsea: Holy crap.
Chelsea: Uh, did you watch the trailer for Elderfield? Because, like, the-
Al: it does look pretty scary as well it's I don't think it's on the same level um but yeah
Chelsea: Okay. Okay, I'm gonna look at the other one, then.
Chelsea: You can call me a coward!
Chelsea: Okay, as soon as I had kids, I was no longer interested in any horror thing.
Al: [laughing]
Chelsea: I don't need my kids possessed. I don't need to be fighting criminals away from my house.
Chelsea: No, thank you.
Al: - Yeah, yeah, when we had kids Rhona,
Al: suddenly just couldn't deal with any film
Al: that has like kids in distress.
Al: She was like, "Nope, nope."
Chelsea: yeah like uh paranormal activity throw the kid away
Al: - Oh, dear.
Chelsea: oh my gosh credit to them though because it looks amazing I just I i can't I could not
Al: - Yeah, I think.
Al: It looks interesting.
Al: It's got very positive reviews.
Al: 82.95% on SteamDB rating.
Al: and it's over 1,500.
Al: So it's doing well, it's selling well and reviewing well.
Al: It is currently 10% off for release and, yeah, that's the thing.
Chelsea: Oh my god, I just looked it up on the Reddit, and there's a picture of this evil demonic
Al: It says, "Cosy distractions from the horrors around you."
Chelsea: cow and it says "thank you for milking me" and they say that's enough Elderfeel for the
Chelsea: day.
Al: [laughs]
Chelsea: Okay, I'm not doing any more research than that.
Al: Oh, dear.
Al: Next up, we have "Ethra."
Al: So this is a game on Kickstarter, the Kickstarter's up now.
Al: It has 19 days to go and it has hit its goal.
Al: It's nearly, it's not far off double its goal, so that's good.
Al: It says, "Ethra, a 3D pixel art open-world RPG.
Al: Adventure RPG game featuring pixel art in a 3D world.
Al: Fight, explore..."
Al: I don't like the grammar here.
Al: "Fight, explore, farming."
Al: You've changed how you're defining these words
Al: halfway through the sentence.
Al: "Fight, explore, farm," or "fighting, exploring, farming."
Chelsea: Farm, yeah.
Chelsea: Yep.
Al: [sighs]
Al: "Trading, economy, crafting, and more."
Al: There's always got to be more.
Chelsea: Could you be more vague than trading economy?
Al: "Ethra..."
Al: [laughs]
Al: Yeah.
Al: "Ethra is a 3D pixel art open-world RPG
Al: with a heavy focus on exploration and combat
Al: where you play two protagonists together
Al: on a journey across the continent
Al: to find your old lie.
Al: You will play as Bob, a farm boy
Al: searching for a more interesting life,
Al: and Vale, a lost child of a rare species
Al: with a natural affinity with magic.
Al: Together, you will explore the continent
Al: filled with ruins, towns, rumours, quests, and trouble
Al: that keeps finding them along the way."
Chelsea: Yeah it looks really cool combining the multiple art styles.
Al: Yeah, um...
Al: It's interesting 'cause it's not like...
Al: When I first read it, I thought it would be
Al: kind of Paper Mario-esque, but it's not.
Al: It's very much a fully 3D world. And your character is 2D-mapped onto that. It's very weird.
Chelsea: Yeah, it's really really cool
Chelsea: Yeah, I find it may make me motion sick if I try it, but no, it looks cool.
Al: Yeah, maybe it's for you, listener.
Chelsea: Could be for you, just like Elderfield.
Al: Next up, Voltaire the Vegan Vampire.
Al: Vampire. So, apparently I missed this when this came out on Steam. It came out on Steam
Al: in 2023, three years ago, and it released on Switch in 2024. It is now coming to PlayStation
Al: and Xbox on the 30th of September this year. And I don't know how I missed it at the time.
Al: Rebel against, sorry, rebel? Rebel against your legacy. That's just the perfect case
Al: of an English word, two English words that are spelled the same. Rebel against your legacy
Al: in this farming action roguelite. Tend your spooky farm by day and defend your crops from
Al: creepers at night. Upgrade Voltaire, youngest son of Dracula, with devious new abilities
Al: and discover dozens of new plants to cultivate. Send Dad a message, a vegan life is no missed
Al: steak. Chelsea, if we had a pound for every game that we've talked about this month where
Al: you play the child of Dracula, we would have two pounds. Which is very weird.
Chelsea: I don't know, it's... that's a very specific thing to go after.
Al: Because what are the chances? That would be interesting. Where's the Voltaire and Moonlight
Chelsea: Maybe they're siblings.
Chelsea: Oh yeah, yeah, I didn't even realize this game, but yeah, it's several years old.
Al: but now it's coming to Xbox and PlayStation.
Al: I'm trying to figure out where the rogue-lite part of it.
Chelsea: See, I see the name and I want to say "Volitaire," like "Solitaire."
Al: No, there's no second vowel there.
Chelsea: No.
Al: Voltaire.
Chelsea: But see, they could have the minigame, like they do in Moonlight Peaks,
Al: No, I can't.
Chelsea: where you have the card game.
Chelsea: They could have had another minigame in this one with cards.
Al: Ha.
Al: I'm guessing you just can die,
Al: and if you die, you have to restart, maybe?
Al: 'Cause it looks like there's a,
Al: defend the crops against Dracula's army of ghoulish minions,
Al: hell-bent on denying Voltaire his hard-earned oatmeal shake.
Al: Embrace vampiric dark powers
Al: to defeat the bosses sent by Dracula.
Al: When his lesser minions fail, overcome Dracula's power and inherit his reign through much greener
Al: means.
Al: Yeah, don't sweat it, there's always a chance to try dieting again this time with new knowledge
Al: and abilities.
Al: So yeah, I suspect you'd just prevail over every metaphorical pickle Voltaire may find
Al: himself in or risk the temptation of his bloodlust munching on a neck or two.
Al: So you fail if you drink someone's blood? Maybe?
Chelsea: Interesting- okay, that's a high stakes game.
Al: Yeah, well, there you go. Ha ha haaaaaa! And finally, we have Bokumono, this is the story
Chelsea: Get it? Like vampire steak? Ha ha ha!
Chelsea: [laughs]
Al: of seasons, or, you know, what originally was called Harvest Moon. Bokumono have announced,
Al: well, it's marvellous, have announced that there's a new Bokumono game. Always has to
Al: be confusing. And this is, we don't know for certain what this would be called in English,
Chelsea: [chuckles]
Al: But the translation seems to be...
Al: The Story of Seasons, Your Wonderful Life, and this is a mixed reality game.
Al: So, uh, you know, like, where they augment - I - here's - okay - here's a little - here's
Al: a little rant from me for today.
Al: Here's - uh - here's what I'm going to give.
Al: Mixed reality seems to be a term that people created because they didn't want to use augmented
Al: reality.
Al: What seemed - what I find annoying, right, is you - you - you had virtual reality, which
Al: is a headset, and you're completely within this virtual reality.
Al: You're not seeing anything of the outside world.
Al: And then there's augmented reality, which is where you have reality, but then you have
Al: stuff on top of that.
Al: It's augmented.
Al: The reality has been augmented.
Al: Now, what's - yes, like Pokemon Go, but also like some things with virtual reality headsets
Al: where they put things on top of the world, right?
Al: So like, there was a game I played a while ago - I can't remember what it was called
Al: - where I had little farms in my office on the virtual reality headset.
Al: It was.
Chelsea: Oh, that's so cool!
Al: It was really fun.
Al: But what seems to annoy me is people seem to not understand what augmented reality is,
Al: and then created this term called mixed reality, which is just the same as augmented reality,
Al: because what mixed reality is, is the world, but also other stuff on top of that, which
Al: you might understand as the description I just gave for augmented reality.
Al: So I don't understand why we are, like, creating this new term, which is - because people always
Al: associate augmented reality as being a cross between virtual reality and augmented reality.
Al: But what is that?
Al: What is a cross between virtual reality, which is where there is no real world, and augmented
Al: reality, which is real world and not real world?
Al: How is there a cross between that?
Al: That's called augmented reality.
Chelsea: Exactly.
Al: So I can't - I cannot for the life of me figure out whether people just decided to rename
Al: augmented reality to mixed reality, or whether they just truly didn't understand what augmented
Al: reality was and...
Al: tried to create a new thing, but it's the same thing.
Chelsea: Yeah, because that seems like the same thing to me.
Al: So there's my complaint. Anyway, so, mixed reality, augmented reality, whatever.
Al: This is a game where you seem to overlay a farm on top of your real world.
Al: What we're not sure about is whether this is like a phone game or whether it's for, you know,
Al: virtual reality headsets.
Chelsea: I can't imagine playing that, like Harvest Moon, Story of Seasons on a VR set.
Al: I mean, it depends what it is, right? We don't know what the gameplay will look like. It's not
Chelsea: Yeah, yeah.
Al: going to be like a normal Story of Seasons game, right? It's not going to be story-heavy or
Al: something. I suspect it will be much like the game that I played a while ago, which is laying things
Al: on top of the world and having a little farm that you can just come back to every so often.
Al: Something like that, I suspect, but we really don't know.
Chelsea: That also confuses me, because I have a wonderful life already, Story of Seasons.
Al: This is your wonderful life. Your, your wonderful life.
Chelsea: YOUR wonderful life. No one else's. Yours. Your wonderful life.
Al: Because it's yours. It's your own. Now, the reason, the reason why I wonder whether this
Chelsea: It's yours! You're not playing...
Al: will be a virtual reality headset thing is because, if you have a look in the article I posted,
Al: the image that they use has a, like a, what's it called, a hand, but it's not a real hand.
Al: It's clearly a virtual hand and that kind of looks, it doesn't look exactly the same,
Al: but it kind of looks like when you have a Metaquest headset on and you have your hands out,
Al: it, like, creates an outline of your hands and it kind of looks like that.
Al: And that's obviously not something you would have on a mobile app if you were doing something like
Al: that. So, I, I mean, people are talking about phones and stuff like that. I have a feeling
Al: it's not going to be for phones and it's going to be for headsets instead.
Al: But we shall see. We don't know. They haven't given us any information. This one screenshot
Al: is all we have. Don't know when it's coming out, what it is, how much it is,
Chelsea: Lots of speculation in there.
Al: what it's for, anything like that. But when has that ever stopped us?
Chelsea: We can speculate.
Al: So, yeah, we'll see. They have confirmed that this is not the game that they already showed
Al: a little bit of in the anniversary video last month. So, there is a traditional
Al: Story of Seasons game still coming, this is not insta-
Al: This is not the new Story of Seasons, it is a side game of some kind.
Chelsea: >> Okay. It is important.
Al: Which is important to some people.
Chelsea: You don't want that to be your big announcement.
Al: Yeah, it's an interesting idea of doing something different,
Al: but that's not going to make you money.
Chelsea: No. Woohoo! Yes.
Al: All right, that's the news.
Al: Let us talk about some demos.
Al: So I played three demos.
Al: When I say played, I don't really mean I played three demos.
Al: I want to talk about the first two demos that I "played" with heavy quotation marks.
Al: First up was Mayday, the Survival Island.
Al: I'm really intrigued by this game still.
Al: This has not stopped me being interested in this game.
Al: But I tried to play this demo on my, you know, my portable, my not Steam Deck.
Al: And it didn't work.
Al: It just, it loaded up the game and there was no controller input whatsoever.
Al: It just wouldn't work.
Al: So I don't know what the problem with this is.
Al: I don't know whether it's a weird settings thing or what,
Al: because the game on Steam says it supports controllers,
Al: and it specifically says it supports my controller,
Al: which the setting there uses my controller
Al: that is on my device.
Al: It says that it should work.
Al: And the demo specifically says
Al: it supports controllers as well,
Al: but it clearly didn't work.
Al: So I don't know what the deal is there,
Al: whether there's a bug
Al: or whether there's some weird settings thing
Al: that I don't know about in my device.
Al: I don't know what the deal is with that.
Chelsea: Mm-hmm.
Al: But all I know is it didn't work.
Chelsea: That's frustrating.
Al: So that's why I say played with heavy quotation marks,
Al: because I loaded up the game
Al: and I literally could do nothing.
Chelsea: Ah, no.
Al: Because the touchscreen wasn't working either,
Al: which quite often the touchscreen works
Al: instead of like a mouse or keyboard.
Al: So that wasn't even working either.
Al: So I don't know what the deal is there.
Al: Next up, I played Cropia.
Al: This game did work, and did play,
Al: but unfortunately, I did not enjoy it.
Al: So it's a 3D game,
Al: the graphics is very kind of,
Al: what's the word I'm looking for?
Al: Polygonal?
Chelsea: Okay. Yeah.
Al: You know, like the 3D version of pixelated.
Al: It's clearly very specific in its art style.
Al: I was not a fan of how, like, the controller,
Al: that the character moved.
Al: and the controls and stuff like that. It felt like it could be good, but there's a lot of
Al: missing quality of life improvements that just made me very frustrated with this game.
Al: So, like, for example, you have a hotbar, like you have in Stardew, but it's like a five-click
Al: process to add things into the hotbar, which was very frustrating. The hotbar is like a different
Al: actual bag, but actually trying to move things between the two was very frustrating. And like
Al: your overall storage was quite, it's just lots of little things like that, you know, that can be very
Al: frustrating. So I reckon if they, if they fixed that up and they made like the the actual experience
Al: of using the game, that I would definitely get back into this and try it more because I'm intrigued
Al: by what it's doing. It has like a big, did you ever play My Time at Portia?
Chelsea: No, I haven't, but I heard that their UI is a bit better than what you're explaining.
Al: So it was, yeah, so it was big on crafting but what I didn't like about its crafting is like
Al: you show like this weird 3D thing that you're crafting and you have to like,
Al: in the game, you have to like align the pieces that you're putting into the crafting machine
Al: in 3D and I really did not like that. Some people really did. I did not like that at all.
Chelsea: Oh, okay.
Al: This feels like it's doing that, but…
Al: less. So it's like, you've got this big crafting machine, but you just click on it, you throw the
Al: stuff in, and it crafts it. You don't have to physically make them move into the right space.
Chelsea: Oh, it's like a minigame within it.
Al: Yeah, exactly, it feels better to me. So I'm intrigued with what it's doing,
Al: but they need to do a lot of work on how the game actually plays, I think, before it's good.
Chelsea: How long did you play for?
Al: Maybe an hour?
Al: Something like that? Definitely enough to know that I couldn't keep playing it.
Chelsea: Okay.
Chelsea: Okay, you gave it a fair chance then.
Al: Yeah, I think so. I think so. So it's been out for about a month and they've had it.
Al: Like it's been in 1.0 for a month and they have released an update. So I don't know,
Al: maybe they'll add some more. I feel like the fact that it was in early access for so long
Al: makes me think that maybe they won't because I feel like they would have dealt with these things.
Al: It's also possible that these issues are only in the demo and not in the main game.
Chelsea: Yeah, maybe. Okay.
Al: I don't know when the demo was last updated. Last updated April of this year.
Al: So you would think so. It first came out in October last year. I don't know. This is the
Al: problem though. If you've got a demo, you've got to make sure it's up to date for the game because
Al: like if the game's like the demo, I don't want to play it. But if the game is better than the
Al: demo, then maybe I do. But I don't want to buy just in case, you know. So there we are. Right,
Al: my third game later. I want Chelsea to talk about her first.
Chelsea: So the first one I played is Danchi Days.
Chelsea: Loved it.
Chelsea: It has Game Boy Advance graphics that you play on the PC,
Chelsea: and you basically play as this little girl who moves back
Chelsea: to the Danchi, which is like a community apartment
Chelsea: sort of building in Japan.
Chelsea: But your grandmother has dementia.
Chelsea: So right off the bat, I'm like, oh, great.
Al: Uh-oh, here we go!
Chelsea: I'm going to cry.
Chelsea: Great start.
Chelsea: Yeah.
Chelsea: Great game to play when you're in a terrible-
Chelsea: -head space. But no, so basically the thing that kept the community thriving when your grandmother was younger was this summer festival.
Chelsea: And you think, "Oh, in order to cure my grandma's dementia, I'm going to host this festival again." And you get help from this god that's like a cat bee, and apparently he used to know your grandmother and they used to run the festival together.
Chelsea: So you basically go around the community inviting the in the demo. Anyway, you go around inviting
Chelsea: neighbors to this festival and you have to do little tasks for them in order for them to RSVP and some of them will only RSVP through your computer, because it's, I guess it takes place a little sooner, like earlier in the times.
Chelsea: But, so like emails like this big new thing. And then you can go to different parts of the map, and you do almost Tai Chi to use your senses, and you play these mini games for these people.
Chelsea: But, yeah, I think the full demo was amazing.
Chelsea: It's about 90 minutes, and you can invite 10, 10 residents, and they all have different personalities and it is so heartfelt and you can do flashbacks to when the community was thriving and stuff and it's just, it's very very emotional.
Chelsea: But it's great the graphics are great the dialogue is very charming.
Chelsea: I really enjoyed it. So I'm excited for it to be released. I think it's October.
Al: Yes, the 29th of October, so.
Chelsea: October 29. Yes, yes. So no I recommend it, but it's very heartfelt.
Al: Okay.
Chelsea: Have you looked at it at all? Have you tried it at all?
Al: I haven't tried it, no, I've looked at it.
Al: I don't know if it's for me.
Al: It feels, I suspect, so it feels very much like,
Al: what was the other one that I played,
Al: which was my summer vacation or something like that?
Al: It's kind of a standard Japanese trope of like,
Al: summer holidays and you're doing stuff.
Chelsea: Okay. Yeah.
Al: And I find that those games, for me,
Al: feel a bit directionless.
Al: How did it feel in terms of where to go?
Al: And I know this is a lot, this sounds ridiculous
Al: coming from someone who got into this genre
Al: through Stardew, the ultimate directionless game.
Al: But tell me, how did it feel?
Al: Did you feel like you had a clear direction to go?
Al: Or was it just like, 'Hey, here's a million things, which one do you want to do?'
Chelsea: Now I felt like there was pretty direct because some put some characters you could only invite after you've done certain tasks for other ones
Chelsea: And then you could ask your cappy friend for hints of like who should I go see so there is a plot driven for that
Chelsea: But there's no rush really
Chelsea: To end your day like you don't end your day until you do your tasks for that day
Chelsea: And then you go to bed because you're tired
Chelsea: But yeah, it can be open-ended I would say a little bit, but again, it's hard to tell by the demo
Chelsea: But you can a lot of the map was blocked off, too
Chelsea: But yeah, I felt like I had a sense of what I had to do I
Chelsea: Feel like as the game opens up, you'll just kind of be thrown into whatever you want
Chelsea: But yeah from the demo is pretty directive just to get a hang of the the concepts of the game
Al: Yeah, yeah, how did it feel control-wise?
Chelsea: I was pretty good. Um, I
Chelsea: Did I play on there? No, I played on keyboard
Chelsea: It was pretty easy, you just use X to open your stuff, and you just use the direction pad
Chelsea: There's not a ton of controls that you need to do, even for the mini-games, it's like
Chelsea: Make this grid move onto this side of the grid, or move this item, so there wasn't a lot of directions you could really go
Chelsea: So I felt pretty smooth
Al: Fair enough. Any complaints?
Chelsea: I don't know, well, no, I've wanted more, but it's a demo, right? So it's hard, like, so much
Al: Oh, come on. Your only complaint can't be "I want more". That's such a boring complaint, Chelsea.
Chelsea: I feel like if you're
Al: Yes, the game was perfect. It just wasn't enough.
Chelsea: Yeah, no, I found the mini-games, maybe, I'm totally contradicting myself, but there was a little bit of confusion on what the directions were
Chelsea: And there are some parts that were locked behind achievements, I'll say, so you get these things called sense stars
Chelsea: So you'll play the mini-game, and if you do it in a certain amount of steps, you get points, and then those points help unlock other parts of the map
Chelsea: of the map. So I wish that
Chelsea: was just a bit more clear. But yeah, a lot of the map was
Chelsea: blocked off, unfortunately, which I know is common in a
Chelsea: demo. But yes, no, I do want more. That's really promising.
Chelsea: But they put a lot of effort into it. So I can't wait to see
Al: All right. Well, the final demo for this episode is Farm and Feast, which I believe Chelsea played
Chelsea: [laughs]
Al: as well. I don't know how much you played, though. Did you get to the end of the demo?
Chelsea: Yeah.
Chelsea: No.
Al: No. That's fine. I did. I did, yeah. And, well, let's just put it this way. I hit the end of the
Chelsea: You did?
Al: demo, and I went, "Oh, I want to keep playing!" So, yeah. So, that will tell you how I feel about
Chelsea: There you go, that's promising.
Al: this game. I...
Al: this game is great. So, I want to try and summarize it a little bit. So, you're running
Al: a cafe. It's... I feel like people will talk about this like... what's the... what's the restaurant
Al: game? The, like, multiplayer? Overcooked. People will compare it to Overcooked, but it is... it
Chelsea: Overcooked?
Al: does... it's not... it's not Overcooked. So, first up, you're not actually doing the cooking. You...
Al: you have a chef who does the cooking. You are the... the... the waitress. And so, your job is to run
Al: the restaurant and do the waitressing, but you can also hire other waiters and waitresses as well.
Al: So, you don't even need to do that as you continue on the game. You're running the restaurant,
Al: essentially, but you're also running a farm and using the farm to gather ingredients for your
Al: meals. Now, what I really like about this is the... the morning. So, you've got, like, two stages of
Al: of the day. There's the morning and then there's after you open the restaurant.
Al: The morning there is no time limit, there is no stamina, you can do as much as you want
Al: in that time. Full stop, no restrictions.
Chelsea: Yeah, I really enjoyed that because I was I kept looking at it like oh my god the day's gonna pass but it didn't even move
Al: It doesn't. Not even. I absolutely love that. Now I do understand that some people
Al: will find that weird and might find it a little bit frustrating because they can't control
Al: themselves and they will continue to like do stuff forever, but you know what? I spent like a good
Al: half an hour one of the days just cleaning the entire farm, seeing how big it was,
Al: chopping down all the trees, getting rid of all the weeds, picking up everything that was there,
Al: and I love it. I love that I could do that.
Al: It was so good. There was a little bit of... did you ever listen to the Sugardew Island episode?
Chelsea: I don't know if I did, I don't think so.
Al: It was the first game on this podcast that I've actively said is a bad game rather than just
Al: saying not for me. But one of the things that I did actually like about it was they did the
Al: same thing where your day is like split in two and the time does not progress without you telling it
Al: to progress essentially. It was the same sort of thing you ran a shop. So you did the farming in
Al: the morning and then you opened a shop in the evening. Same thing here. You run a farm in the
Al: morning and then you open your restaurant for the rest of the day. I actually really like this as a
Chelsea: Yeah.
Al: concept and I feel like more games need to look into this.
Chelsea: Yeah, Bistro did that too. I enjoyed that a lot.
Al: It did, but I didn't like that game. So that's a whole other thing. But no, you're right. You're
Al: right. It did have that same thing and I do like that because I like the idea of like these...
Al: there are these type parts of the day and these are the.
Al: things you focus on in this part of the day and I think it might help people who get overwhelmed
Al: by these types of games where there's so much to do where you're like well that's fine don't
Al: focus on this bit just now right you're farming don't think about the restaurant just now
Al: think about the farming and then when you're done that it's like don't think about the
Al: farming you're doing the restaurant although do you know what I really like is you can
Al: continue to farm when the restaurants open if you want.
Chelsea: Isn't that so funny? I thought that was hilarious.
Al: I'm just running up running away from my restaurant and the people who are wanting food to go
Al: go and water some potatoes.
Chelsea: Yeah, order some mushrooms halfway through.
Al: The other thing I really like is, so obviously early game you will have very little in terms
Al: of ingredients. I think you start out where you can, there's the mushrooms that are growing
Al: around which you pick for mushroom soup, and there's also a bunch of herbs. But then there's
Al: not very much you can do the first couple of days until you get a decent amount of money
Al: and then you can buy some seeds, but what you can do is if you do have some.
Al: And because it's a real-time restaurant game, you can order things online and they will be delivered to you after a period of time, so you can kind of gamble a little bit and be like, "Oh, I'm running out of ingredients. Let me buy some, welcome some people in and get their orders."
Al: And yes, they might be ordering something I don't have,
Al: but it's on its way and you're kind of like.
Al: Just risking things a little bit.
Al: I quite like that aspect of it.
Al: You can do the stress if you want,
Al: or you can just ignore them
Al: and not bring them into the restaurant.
Al: I don't know if you experienced this,
Al: but so there's, if certain things take too long,
Al: they're unhappy and they're less likely to pay,
Al: you know, give you tips and stuff like that.
Al: But I'd never noticed them leave the queue
Al: to get into the restaurant.
Chelsea: - No, I never, yeah, I never saw anyone leave.
Al: So I noticed them complaining about the.
Al: Stuff coming. I never got to the point where it was long enough that they would have done anything about it. I don't know whether they just would have given me less money or whether they would have left. But yeah, they never seem to leave the queue at the door. So you can just go. I'm not going to let anyone in. I don't have the food if you want to play things safe. Or you can do what I did and let everybody in and then just be stressed about the fact that food hasn't arrived yet.
Al: Especially when you have like 5 tables that are all full of people and then you've got one chef who's stressed.
Al: The other thing I really liked was you. So a lot of it is kind of like, oh, you welcome them, you bring them in, you give them a table and then they will take a little bit of time and then they'll be like, oh, I know what to order. You take their order. You kind of like have to manually choose what the things are. It's like this meal with these changes to it and then these drinks and then you put the order in and then the chef goes and cooks it.
Chelsea: [laughs]
Al: And you go get the drinks and take them to them. And then when the food's ready, you go take it to the table and then they eat it and then they say they're done. They want to pay. And what you do is you manually put in the amount of money. And what's interesting about it is the amount that you put in doesn't have to be the exact amount that's on the bill.
Al: And if you charge more, the more you charge over the amount that it is, the higher the risk is that it goes wrong.
Al: a chance they just pay it and then give you a tip as well right so you can kind of you can kind of
Chelsea: Interesting.
Al: gamble how much you're going to charge them and actually you can make a lot more money that way
Al: obviously not ethical but really interesting now what I will say is if they if they don't want to
Al: pay it I think they just give you the amount on the bill and they don't give you any tip
Al: so you are gambling there because the the tips can be a decent amount because obviously this is a game made by Americans
Al: um but it's it's yeah so you don't just go in and say like oh i'm charging you a thousand because
Chelsea: [laughter]
Al: they they won't give you a thousand and they won't give you a tip you'll just yeah it just
Al: backfires if you do that I did I did try that out once because why not let's see what happens
Chelsea: Okay, I didn't try. I wasn't... I wasn't risky.
Al: come on it's the demo if you're not going to risk it in the demo where are you going to risk it
Al: Um, but yeah, like there were times where I was like it was 50 and I was charging them
Al: and they were giving me that and they also gave me a tip as well.
Al: So you can rack it up if you, if you play it a little bit, but obviously there's a chance
Al: they just don't.
Al: And then, then you're like, Oh, didn't even get a tip from that one.
Al: You know?
Al: And it's a bit frustrating, but it's, it's fun.
Al: I like that kind of risk aspect to it.
Al: Um, and I feel like that's kind of what this is going for.
Al: It's not like huge, massive, stressful game, but it's about how much risk you give.
Al: like we were talking about you can just like leave the restaurant.
Al: and go and farm some more and like that will give you more ingredients tomorrow
Al: but you're obviously risking the fact that you don't get back in time to give someone their food.
Chelsea: Right.
Al: So I enjoyed that.
Chelsea: Yeah.
Chelsea: I hated that game with the soda.
Al: it is so it's it's so weird so like yeah let me do you want to do you want to explain how it works
Chelsea: I was like, "Why are we even doing this?"
Chelsea: Sure, so for everything else, you're just using your controller like A, B, Y, X.
Chelsea: But with the-- when you go to the drink fridge to get drinks,
Chelsea: you have to do this like aiming game where you make the angle
Chelsea: So that you could throw it onto-
Chelsea: your tray but if you miss it it goes on the floor but I didn't get so far in the
Chelsea: demo so I don't know if it's only for the drinks or like do other mechanics
Chelsea: come in later in the game where you actually have to do the minigame?
Al: There are some other things, so like, after a while you'll start unlocking pouring water for them, and that is another another little minigame.
Chelsea: Oh god, okay.
Al: But yeah, it's so weird because like the main stuff is just like you move around, you press a button to do a thing, right?
Al: And then they're like, "Oh, but here's some random minigames for throwing drinks on a tray!"
Chelsea: Yeah, like, I was- I was using my Xbox controller for the- for moving around the restaurant, but for the- for the drinks and stuff, I had to use my mouse.
Al: It's so weird!
Al: Yeah.
Chelsea: I'm like, "I don't know what the heck I'm doing here, okay?"
Al: I will say I will say it worked quite well, I found, like the controller worked fine for it. I was just using the analog stick to aim, so I and also like I complained about the other games when they had issues, the controller worked really well here, the controller support was pretty good, I didn't I didn't find anything I couldn't do with the controller, it was it was really well done.
Chelsea: Okay.
Al: But yeah, it clearly wants to be silly, and I can't decide whether it's gone all in or not, I'll have to...
Al: I'm buying this game, full stop, like I've already scheduled time in November, like when I'm playing this game because I like I enjoyed it that much, but it will be interesting to see whether it continues to be silly or not, because it's like it's not, it doesn't feel all in on the silly, right? Like there's some silly with the drinks, with the watering, the watering feels a little bit silly, where you've got like this silly hose, like you don't have a watering can like normal farming games, you have a hose, and you have to...
Chelsea: [laughs] The hose.
Chelsea: No, they put all of their resources into the hose physics.
Al: Which is fantastic, may I say, but you pull this hose from the watering container, and you have to like aim it, and move where you're aiming, and walk around at the same time, it's very silly, but then like the farming is just like normal farming other than that, so it's like I don't know where there's more silliness going to come in, I don't know.
Al: You run out of the water tank, you then have to pump water into the water tank, and that's another little mini game, so yeah, there is definitely stuff there, but I don't know, yeah, I can't decide whether it's just trying to be silly, or whether it's like here's just a few silly bits and pieces, and I can't decide what I would prefer.
Chelsea: Oh, just go all in if you're gonna do it at all.
Al: Yeah, I just, it'll be interesting to see whether that expands or not.
Chelsea: The art style is cool though, I like that you look like Fisher Price little people.
Al: I think, yeah, I quite like it. It's an interesting art style. I'm enjoying looking at it.
Al: Yeah, I like this game. This is a fun game. I'm going to play this game.
Chelsea: Mhm. Yeah, maybe depending on the price I'll- I'll grab it, but we'll see.
Al: We shall see.
Al: You wanted to talk about the coke?
Chelsea: Yeah, okay, so they're just straight up using the word "coke" instead of "cola"
Al: They are.
Chelsea: and, like, don't let me be the one to get the "cease and desist" letter on you, but, like,
Chelsea: pretty sure you don't have that permission.
Al: Maybe they do.
Chelsea: Maybe they do! Wouldn't there be, like, a TM beside it then?
Al: I find it really weird that Coke is trademarked. Like, Coca-Cola is the name. The name isn't Coke.
Chelsea: Yeah.
Al: Why do they have that trademarked? It's not their name.
Chelsea: I have no idea. That's a whole other episode.
Chelsea: But, no, it's just a little point. I was like, "Oh, that doesn't say 'cola', that says 'coke'."
Chelsea: Interesting. No, but, yeah, no, it's- looks like a good game for- it seems like your type of game.
Al: Haha, what does that mean?
Chelsea: You like your farming! That's the whole point of the show!
Al: Yeah, I don't like all farming games
Chelsea: Well, no. But yeah, I find the time management, like, cookie-
Chelsea: -king Mama, Overcooked, that kind of stuff, that one-piece game that's coming out that I know
Chelsea: Kevin's gonna be all over. Those games stress me out a little bit, but I'm a perfectionist,
Al: [laughing]
Chelsea: so it's like, what do you mean you're not gonna give me a 100% tip and my restaurant rating's
Chelsea: only 4.8? I am failing at this game, so maybe it's just not meant for me.
Al: - Yeah, no, that's fine.
Al: Not all games are for everyone.
Al: But I am very much enjoying it.
Al: And I don't feel stressed,
Al: which is what I was a little bit worried about.
Al: Is it, you know, 'cause obviously people use
Al: the comparison with Overcooked.
Al: Is it gonna feel stressed?
Al: No, I thought it was quite fun.
Al: 'Cause like, as you expand,
Al: you gain other ways to make it less stressful.
Al: Like, you know, when you add more tables,
Al: you can also hire more staff.
Al: You can hire more chefs and you can hire waiters.
Al: And it's like, you can either just leave.
Al: it to the hired waiters or you can join in yourself and speed things up and I really like that.
Al: Yeah, no it's really good. It's like you get to the point where like oh there's so many things
Al: I'm doing because you add the like you have to clear the tables, you have to sometimes wipe the
Al: tables, also there can be messes on the floor and then obviously you've got the ordering, you've got
Al: the welcoming people in, you've got pouring them water, you've got getting the drinks, you've got
Al: you know them paying money but it like slowly unlocks
Al: and by the time you've unlocked all of them you have enough money to start hiring people.
Chelsea: Okay, okay, so I- I didn't know that you actually were able to hire other people.
Al: Yeah yeah so no no no and it's um you pay them by hour so um you you basically you you know
Chelsea: I thought you would just expand your restaurant and it's just you.
Al: whether you're going to be able to afford it or not based on whether you're actually good at the
Al: game. Interestingly so one thing about I will say about the hiring people is um the waiters have like
Al: our skill level.
Al: And so they start out being like, their accuracy on taking the orders is only 80% or something,
Al: and you have to train them up to make them better.
Chelsea: Interesting.
Al: The good thing is that training them up just involves paying money.
Al: So it feels a little bit capitalist game, it's like, oh, we could just pay money to
Al: fix things, right?
Chelsea: Well, pay more money!
Al: That's how it works.
Al: Yeah.
Chelsea: Mm-hmm. That's funny. Go take a serving class.
Al: Yeah, yeah, absolutely.
Al: I think I got mine up to like 98% or something like that, which is like, that's good.
Chelsea: Oh wow.
Al: That's good enough.
Al: That's...
Chelsea: How long did you play for?
Al: Oh, good question.
Al: Let me check.
Chelsea: Because I played for maybe 45 minutes or so.
Al: So, I've got, yeah, no, that's, I do honestly think that an hour of a game is enough to
Chelsea: I'll I gave it it yeah
Al: know whether you should continue playing.
Al: I do think that sometimes you need to give it that full hour, but yeah, if you're not
Al: enjoying a game after an hour, you're, like, either you're not going to enjoy it or the
Al: game's badly designed.
Al: I have five hours of playtime on the demo.
Chelsea: Oh, wow. So, is there a certain-- did you reach the end?
Al: Yeah, I've reached the point where it was like, you're done, and I'm like, oh, sad.
Chelsea: [laughs]
Al: And you just couldn't play that save file anymore.
Chelsea: Can you-- [laughs]
Al: So I think you could create a new one, but then obviously you're back to the start, and
Al: I'm like, I'm not going to do that.
Al: I'm just going to wait for the game.
Al: What I don't know is whether you can move progress from the demo to the game.
Chelsea: Okay, that's what my next question was.
Al: I don't know.
Al: I do not know.
Al: They've not said that.
Al: And it's not going to be a deal-breaker for me.
Al: I will be disappointed if I can't, but it won't be a deal-breaker for me, but it won't
Al: be a deal-breaker for me.
Chelsea: Yeah, because for Danchi days you can't- there's no save/transfer.
Al: is kind of, like, specifically designed to show you how to play the game, isn't it?
Al: Or is it from the start of the game?
Chelsea: and it shows it it's like it's from the beginning but
Al: Okay.
Al: Fair enough.
Al: Because just, like, some demos are like, here is a very specific part of the game that you
Al: can play, whereas some it's like you can play X number of hours of the game.
Chelsea: yeah
Chelsea: no it hits you right in the feels from from the first cut scene just to get you emotionally invested
Al: Excellent.
Al: That's how it works.
Al: All right.
Al: Well, that's our demos, then.
Al: Four games.
Al: Uhhhh...
Al: Two of them, we will definitely play again.
Al: Sounds like.
Al: If you're going to play, if you're, sounds like you're going to play Danche Game.
Al: Danche Dem, Danche Days.
Chelsea: yes
Al: And the other ones, we'll see!
Al: Alright, thank you Chelsea for joining me for this episode.
Al: Is there anything you...
Chelsea: No, but thank you for having me, and I'm sorry if people are getting sick of me
Chelsea: And we have the we have the neopets one coming up so there won't be any Kevin toad impressions
Al: I do need to apologize for listeners for leaving that in. It was so overdriven, but I was like,
Chelsea: I'm not as good as impressions as Kevin is
Al: this is obviously terrible and I apologize if it hurt anyone's ears, but it felt so ridiculously
Al: bad that I felt I needed to leave it in because I don't think anybody would have believed
Al: how bad it is if they hadn't heard it. It was just like listening to it going like,
Al: I don't understand what is happening here like it's
Chelsea: I was driving, I was driving while I was listening to it and I almost swerved because I was laughing
Al: like kevin is being raptured or something like I is he being electrocuted is like what's happening
Chelsea: so hard because you told us, you were like, "Regardless of what you're thinking, it's
Chelsea: worse."
Chelsea: I was like, "Oh, I'm sorry."
Al: yeah yeah I suppose we have a chat for the for the regulars team in uh in slack and i
Al: was like honestly you have no idea and even kevin wouldn't know because he didn't listen
Al: and he had an idea of what it would be because he had said it but I was like trust me
Chelsea: [laughs]
Al: trust me whatever you're imagining is worse so bad
Chelsea: It's more than that.
Chelsea: Oh my gosh.
Al: nothing against kevin's imperson impression kevin's impressions are generally good
Chelsea: [laughs]
Al: but my word he was needed to turn that volume down a little bit we love you kevin
Chelsea: Nah, I don't think I can top that, though.
Chelsea: No way I can top that.
Al: All right, well you can
Al: Find the podcast on tumblr and on blue sky at THS pod
Al: You can send us feedback from our website harvest Harvest season club harvest season club
Al: I want to know if there's a demo you have been playing of a game
Al: Recently tell us what it is
Al: You can also find links to everything to do with the podcast including our patreon patreon.com slash THS pod where sometimes we post
Al: bonus episodes
Al: It's that time of year
Al: Yeah, we'll get there well
Chelsea: Yes.
Al: please no you can also get access to our slack where we mock me and apparently now kevin
Chelsea: Maybe we should just get Kevin doing an impersonations episode.
Chelsea: We do it with love.
Al: we do we do all right I think that's everything thank you chelsea again for joining me
Chelsea: Thanks for having me.
Al: thank you listeners for listening and until next time have a good harvest
Chelsea: Have a good harvest.
Theme Tune: The Harvest Season is created by Al McKinley with support from our Patrons including our
Theme Tune: Pro Farmers Kevin, Stuart and Elisa. Our art is done by Micah the Brave and our music is
Theme Tune: done by Nick Burgess. Feel free to visit our website harvestseason.club for show notes
Theme Tune: and links to things we discussed in this episode.
Al: It's funny, it's a very common thing for me at the end of this podcast to just be absolutely
Al: desperate for the toilet. And I don't even know, it's been an hour and a half since
Al: the call started, it's not been that long. I watch films twice as long as this and don't
Al: have this problem. But for some reason, the podcast itself seems to make me need the toilet.
Al: It's ridiculous. Yeah, it's like it's nearly done. I need the toilet.
Chelsea: Your body knows it's on to the next activity.